# MAINAK CHAKRABORTY

+1-240-408-9107 | mchakrab2@student.touro.edu | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

# **OBECTIVE: UI/UX Designer**

I have a passion for finding opportunities that allow me to dive into the role of UI/UX design and to continue my learning journey in UX Design & Product Design. Collaborating with professionals and gaining hands on experience is something I am eagerly looking forward to. Currently I am actively searching for positions where I can contribute to groundbreaking projects, learn from mentors, and further enhance my skills while making an impact in the field of UX Design

# **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Software Skills: Microsoft Suite, Foundational HTML, CSS & JavaScript, Agile Methodology
- Designing Tools: Adobe Figma, Sketch, In Vision, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Balsamiq, Davinci Resolve
- · Community Service: At an NGO working towards education for underprivileged children in Mumbai.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Touro University** – *Graduate Assistant*

# **New York City**

Present

- · As a Graduate Assistant at Touro University, I am at the forefront of shaping the institution's digital presence and engagement.
- Focused on enhancing the university's outreach through multimedia, I specialize in video production and content management for Touro's YouTube channel and website.
- My responsibilities encompass a wide range of skills, including video editing, creating captivating graphics, and curating content that resonates with the university's audience.
- Through my role, I am dedicated to elevating Touro University's online identity and effectively communicating its mission to a global audience.
  - Skills & Interest: Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Media Encoder, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop, Canva.

**Ipsos Research** – Research Associate

#### Mumbai, India

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

# Marketing Strategy & Innovation

- Performed professional market research with extensive experience in identifying target markets, analyzing customer behavior, industry trends, and competition for Mondelez.
- Assisted senior researchers in questionnaire and survey design, conducting business forecasts, and participating in weekly team meetings with managers and leadership.
- Performed seamless cross-functional coordination with field executives, data processing team and finance team, resulting in improving the material receipt success rate by 20% and increasing quality efficiency by 16%
- Managed various vendors related to research work and materials, optimizing payment structures and ensuring high-quality research location and on-time in-home fieldwork.

# **Raptreels Productions** – *Digital Editor*

# Mumbai, India

Jul 2020 - Nov 2021

#### **Commercial Video Editing & Client Support**

- Worked on commercial video editing for clients and provided technical support working one-on-one with in-house team members and freelancers to deliver high-quality content.
- Assisted various contributors to meet deadlines by introducing project matrix, resulting in time savings from 10 to 6 hours per project.
- Implemented seamless sound effects, voices, and music into videos for clients' social media platforms and assembled raw footage using Photoshop to create finalized products.

Bzinga (Zee Essel) – Product Intern

# Mumbai, India

Apr 2020- Jun 2020

### App Development & Digital Marketing

- Managed social media profiles, created monthly content decks with copies and visuals, and analyzed daily reports to share MAU/DAU and YTD user data with UX team for continuous enhancement.
- · Installed Bzinga App on Android/iOS and helped bring down the average cost per install (CPI) from \$0.40 to \$0.25

**RGBA Studios** – *Production Coordinator* 

## Mumbai, India

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

# VFX & Motion Graphics

- Conveyed client requirements, managed production schedules, coordinated manuscript flow, and assembled footage for efficient delivery.
- Effectively provided feedback to process managers and coordinated with Ad agencies and production houses.

# **EDUCATION**

Masters in Web and Multimedia Design

Expected grad Aug 2024

Touro University, New York City

Graduate School of Technology

**Bachelor of Mass Media** 

University of Mumbai, India

MMK College of Commerce & Economics

August 2019

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

	Marketing in Digital World
•	Digital Media and Marketing Principle

GIES School of Business GIES School of Business Jan 2021 Jan 2021

Foundation of Project Management

by Google

Aug 2021

Foundation Of User Experience (UX)

by Google

Sep 2021